Guide to the Nina Rosenblum Papers MSS.558
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series IV. America and Lewis Hine, 1868-2014; 6.26 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes, 1 small flat box, 1 flat file folder, 4 record cartons, 1 film can, and 1 folder in a shared oversized box; 3 VHS; 2 U-matic; 1 16mm_film_reels; 8.78 Gigabytes in 33 computer files
  - Subseries IV.C. Marketing Materials, 1984-2014; .63 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box and 1 large flat box; 27.8 Megabytes in 3 computer files
    This subseries includes materials related to the marketing of the film, such as a one-page description, a VHS cover, poster, and invitiation to the film premiere.
    - Brochure, One-Pager, and VHS Cover, 1984-2014 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Electronic Records -- Posters and DVD Cover, circa 1984-2014; FA_MSS_558_ER_26
    - Opening Gala -- Invitations, Press Release, and Photographs, September 1984 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Poster, 1984 (Box Shared Fales 117, Folder 3)
  - Subseries IV.D. Press, 1982-2014; .44 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box
    This subseries contains publicity materials related to the film, including press releases, interviews, articles, reviews, and a publicity scrapbook.
    - Press Releases, Reviews, and Announcements, 1984-2014 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Scrapbook, 1982-2013 (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
  - Subseries IV.E. Production Materials, 1980-2011; 4.90 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box, 4 record cartons, and 1 film can; 3 VHS; 2 U-matic; 1 16mm_film_reels; 8.73 Gigabytes in 13 computer files
    This subseries consists of production-related materials including film and video recordings (both analog and digital), schedules, and photographs.
    - Electronic Recordings, 2004-2011; FA_MSS_558_ER_27
    - Film and Video Recordings
      - America and Lewis Hine, November 9, 2001 (Box 33, Vhs 558.0494)
      - America and Lewis Hine, November 13, 2001 (Box 32, Vhs 558.0318)
      - America and Lewis Hine, undated (Box 30, U-matic 558.0539)
      - America and Lewis Hine -- Print, undated; cuid41392 (Box 53, 16mm film reels 558.0286)
      - America and Lewis Hine -- Dub, November 9, 2001 (Box 32, Vhs 558.0325)
      - America and Lewis Hine -- Dub, undated (Box 24, U-matic 558.0567)
    - Schedules and Photographs, 1980-1984
      - Electronic Records, FA_MSS_558_ER_28
      - Schedules and Shoot Prints (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Subseries IV.F. Research, 1868-1984; .74 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box, 1 small flat box, and 1 oversized folder; 3.96 Megabytes in 10 computer files
    This series includes research materials used in the making of the film such as articles and other published material, photographs by Lewis Hine, photographs by other Hine's peers, and an informational poster.
    - Articles and Archival Materials, 1905-1984 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Negatives, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Photographs by Hine, 1937
      - Prints (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Digital Photographs, FA_MSS_558_ER_29
    - Photographs by Hine and Others, 1868-1963 (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
    - Poster, 1977 (Flat-file-folder 9 left)
  - Subseries IV.G. Screenings and Festivals, 1984-2013; 1.06 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes and 1 large flat box; 8.24 Megabytes in 3 computer files
    This subseries consists of materials related to the screening of the film and participation in film festivals. Materials include posters, festival programs, and schedules.
    - Photographs, circa 1985-1990; FA_MSS_558_ER_30
    - Posters, 1985-1990 (Box Shared Fales 117, Folder 3)
    - Press, Programs, and Correspondence, 1984-2013 (Box 5, Folder 10, Box 6, Folder 1-2)
- Series V. Through the Wire, 1974-2013; 10.70 Linear Feet in 4 manuscript boxes, 1 medium flat box, 6 record cartons, 2 film cans, 1 cassette box, 2 upright video containers, 1 LP box, 1 small flat box, 1 flat file folder, and 1 folder in a shared oversized box; 9 16mm_film_reels; 19 Quarter_Inch_Audio_Reel; 2 audiocassette; 2 1_Inch_Video_Reel; 2 2_Inch_Videoreel; 4 U-matic; 1 VHS; 7.62 Gigabytes in 14 computer files
  This series consists of production, marketing, and screening-related materials for the film, Through the Wire, released in 1989. Produced in association with Amnesty International, this film examines three female inmates convicted of politically-motivated crimes who were housed in an underground high-security isolation unit located in the federal prison in Lexington, Kentucky. Materials include research materials (articles and letters), audio recordings of interviews with the incarcerated women, letters from viewers, press and publicity, a scrapbook, posters, photographs (both print and digital), and film elements (such as interviews, stills, an Italian master copy for a film festival, and selects for news shows) on various media.
  Arranged alphabetically into four subseries and alphanumerically within each one.
  - Subseries V.A. Marketing Materials, 1988-1991; .63 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box, 1 large flat box, and 1 oversized folder; 25.8 Megabytes in 2 computer files
    This subseries contains materials related to the marketing of the film, such as press releases, posters, and announcement postcards.
    - Posters, 1990 (Box Shared Fales 117, Folder 4, Flat-file-folder 2)
    - Press Releases and Postcards, 1988-1991 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - VHS Cover and Photograph, circa 1990; FA_MSS_558_ER_33
  - Subseries V.B. Press and Awards, 1987-1999; .73 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box and 1 small flat box
    This subseries consists of publicity materials related to the film and awards received by the film and filmmakers. Materials include correspondence, award programs, clippings, reviews, and a publicity scrapbook.
    - Awards and Honors, 1990-1999 (Box 7, Folder 3, Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Clippings and Reviews, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 6, Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Scrapbook, 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Subseries V.C. Production Materials, 1974-2013; 10 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes, 6 record cartons, 1 cassette box, 1 LP box, 2 upright video containers, and 2 film cans; 9 16mm_film_reels; 19 Quarter_Inch_Audio_Reel; 2 audiocassette; 1 1_Inch_Video_Reel; 2 2_Inch_Videoreel; 4 U-matic; 1 VHS; 7.59 Gigabytes in 9 computer files
    This subseries includes materials related to the production of the film, including audio, film, and video recordings (analog and digital); a film script; shoot photographs; and correspondence with the incarcerated women.
    - Articles and Letters/Poems by Incarcerated Women, 1974-1988 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Audio Recordings
      - #3, March 22, 1989 (Box 33, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0471)
      - #4, March 22, 1989 (Box 33, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0470)
      - #6, March 22, 1989 (Box 33, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0474)
      - Inside Women Inside, June 27, 1989 (Box 42, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0506)
      - Lawyers, July 26, 1987 (Box 42, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0504)
      - Manny and Bella, July 26, 1987 (Box 33, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0472)
      - Marianna, undated (Box 33, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0469)
      - Mr. Torres
        - Audio Reel, July 26, 1987 (Box 33, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0467)
        - Audio Reel, July 26, 1987 (Box 33, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0473)
      - Mrs. Rosenberg, August 7, 1989 (Box 42, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0515)
      - OTL 2nd hour -- Nina and Alexandra, April 5, 1990 (Box 62, Audiocassette 558.0227)
      - OTL 3rd hour -- Nina and Alexandra, April 5, 1990 (Box 62, Audiocassette 558.0222)
      - Richard Korn, undated (Box 42, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0513)
      - Rock-A-Bye Baby, undated (Box 42, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0507)
      - Rosenbergers at Home
        - Master, January 14, 1989 (Box 33, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0466)
        - Audio Reel, January 14, 1989 (Box 33, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0468)
        - Audio Reel, January 14, 1989 (Box 42, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0505)
      - Roundtable Discussion and Linda Singing/Talking, March 5, 1988 (Box 42, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0521)
      - U/88, 7/49, January 19, 1989 (Box 42, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0503)
      - Untitled, August 8, 1989 (Box 42, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0522)
    - Correspondence, 1988-2013 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Electronic Recordings, circa 1987-1989; FA_MSS_558_ER_34
    - Film Recordings
      - "Black Panther", June 15, 1989; cuid41394 (Box 55, 16mm film reels 558.0038)
      - High Security Unit
        - Roll Nos. 1-3, September 13, 1989; cuid41397 (Box 55, 16mm film reels 558.0037)
        - Roll Nos. 4-6, September 13, 1989; cuid41398 (Box 55, 16mm film reels 558.0032)
        - Roll Nos. 7-8, September 14, 1989; cuid41399 (Box 55, 16mm film reels 558.0031)
      - "Protecting the People", June 26, 1989; cuid41395 (Box 55, 16mm film reels 558.0035)
      - Print -- Reel 2, undated; cuid41400 (Box 49, 16mm film reels 558.0284)
      - Print -- Reel 1, undated; cuid41401 (Box 50, 16mm film reels 558.0285)
      - "We Demand Freedom", June 30, 1989; cuid41396 (Box 55, 16mm film reels 558.0033)
      - "The Woman's Film", June 15, 1989; cuid41393 (Box 55, 16mm film reels 558.0036)
    - Production and Publicity Photographs, Slides, and Negatives, 1988-1990 (Box 6, Folder 9, Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Script, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Video Recordings
      - Female High Security Unit, November 11, 1988 (Box 24, U-matic 558.0644)
      - "Female High Security Unit" -- Show Reel -- NBC's Today Show and ABC's 20/20 -- Produced and Co-Produced by Nina Rosenblum, undated (Box 32, Vhs 558.0319)
      - Italian Master Recording, 2007; FA_MSS_558_ER_116
      - Lexington -- Reel 2, Part 2 -- With Timecode, undated (Box 46, U-matic 558.0642)
      - NBC's Today Show Selects -- Produced by Daedalus Productions
        - High Security/American Gulag, undated (Box 23, U-matic 558.0643)
        - High Security/American Gulag -- Part 2, undated (Box 61, U-matic 558.0003)
      - Through the Wire -- Master, February 6, 1990 (Box 47, 2 inch videoreel 558.0001)
      - Through the Wire, undated (Box 48, 2 inch videoreel 558.0002)
  - Subseries V.D. Screenings and Film Festivals, 1988-2004; .69 Linear Feet in 1 legal box and 1 medium flat box; 4.66 Megabytes in 3 computer files
    This subseries contains materials related to the screening of the film and participation in film festivals. Materials include festival programs, correspondence, and screening posters.
    - Correspondence, Programs, and Press, 1988-2004 (Box 7, Folder 4-5)
    - Photographs, circa 1988-1990; FA_MSS_558_ER_35
    - Posters, 1990-2001 (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Series VI. Liberators: Fighting on Two Fronts in WWII, 1937-2011; 5.66 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes, 4 record cartons, 1 cassette box, and 2 flat file folders; 1 Betacam; 4 VHS; 9.70 Gigabytes in 15 computer files
  This series consists of materials related to Liberators: Fighting on Two Fronts in WWII, an Academy Award nominated feature documentary released in 1992. The film chronicles the all-Black 761st Tank Battalion, one of only a few segregated units to see combat in Europe during World War II and assist in the liberation of concentration camps. Materials include posters, press, photographs, a scrapbook, and film elements (such as a news segment, interviews with participants, and interviews with filmmakers) on various media. After the film's release, there was some dispute over its accuracy; materials related to the controversy, including articles, press releases, correspondence, and a playscript, are included.
  - Subseries VI.A. Awards and Honors, 1992-1993; .44 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box; 1.44 Megabytes in 3 computer files
    This subseries includes materials related to awards won by the film and its filmmakers. Materials include correspondence, an invitiation, and awards program.
    - Correspondence, Invitation, and Programs, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Photographs, circa 1992-1993; FA_MSS_558_ER_36
  - Subseries VI.B. Controversy, 1993-1998; .88 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes
    This subseries consists of materials related to the controversy over the accuracy of the film, such as the filmmakers' response, press releases, and a playscript.
    - Correspondence, Press, and Press Releases, 1993-1998 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Roth, Ari -- Goodnight Irene -- Play Based on Controversy, 1994-1996 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Subseries VI.C. Marketing Materials, 1992-1995; .45 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box and 2 oversized folders; 48 kilobytes in 1 computer file
    This subseries includes materials related to the marketing of the film, such as posters, postcards, press releases, and a VHS cover.
    - DVD Cover, circa 1995; FA_MSS_558_ER_37
    - Posters, 1992 (Flat-file-folder 9 left, Flat-file-folder 8 Left)
    - Press Release, Brochure, and Postcard, 1992-1995 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Subseries VI.D. Press and Reviews, 1991-2003; 1.52 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box and 1 record carton; 1 VHS
    This subseries contains publicity materials related to the film, such as reviews, clippings, a publicity scrapbook, and an interview.
    - Clippings, 1991-1999 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Scrapbook, 1992-2003 (Box 9, Folder 4-5)
    - "Survivors of the Shoah" with Benjamin Bender -- Interviewed by Nina Rosenblum, February 23, 1996 (Box 32, Vhs 558.0333)
  - Subseries VI.E. Production Materials, 1990-2012; 4.13 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes and 3 record cartons; 1 Betacam; 3 VHS; 9.67 Gigabytes in 10 computer files
    This subseries includes material related to the production of the film, such as video recordings, photographs, a proposal, and correspondence.
    - Correspondence, 1990-2011 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Electronic Recordings, 2004-2012; FA_MSS_558_ER_39
    - Photographs, 1991
      - Prints and Negatives (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Electronic Records, FA_MSS_558_ER_38
    - Proposal and Storyboard, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Slides by Simon Chaput, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 4-7)
    - Video Recordings
      - Christopher Ruddy, undated (Box 33, Vhs 558.0493)
      - Liberators at Rikers Island, December 18, 1992 (Box 24, Betacam 558.0576)
      - Miles Educational Films -- Liberators: Fighting on Two Fronts in WWII, December 15, 1992 (Box 25, Vhs 558.0100)
      - Miles Educational Films -- Liberators: Fighting on Two Fronts in WWII -- License Copy -- Reels 1-5, February 9, 1994 (Box 25, Vhs 558.0101)
  - Subseries VI.F. Research, 1937-1990; .88 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes
    This subseries consists of research materials used in the making of the film, such as published articles, interviews, and photographs.
    - Articles, Interviews, and Archival Material, 1945-1990 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Photographs and Negative, 1937-1945 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Subseries VI.G. Screenings and Festivals, 1993-2006; .44 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box; 33 kilobytes in 1 computer file
    This subseries contains materials related to the screening of the film and participation in film festivals. Materials include correspondence, festival programs, and schedules.
    - Programs, Schedules, and Correspondence, 1993-1999 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Screening Announcement, 2006; FA_MSS_558_ER_40
- Series VII. The Untold West: The Black West, 1992-1998; 8.85 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes, 1 cassette box, 6 record cartons, and 1 medium flat box; 1 Hi8; 10 Betacam_SP; 1 D-2; 2 U-matic; 5 VHS; 16.9 Gigabytes in 39 computer files
  This series covers The Black West, episode two of a three-part TBS series The Untold West. Released in 1993, the episode describes the achievements of Black cowboys and frontiersmen. Materials related to the episode's production, marketing, and awards include photographs and slides, a scrapbook, and film elements (such as "The Making of" tapes, spot clips, a press tape, a dub version, and interviews) on various media.
  Arranged alphabetically into five subseries and alphanumerically within each one.
  - Subseries VII.A. Administrative Materials, 1993-1998; .88 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes
    This subseries includes office files, such as correspondence, an informational flyer, and a VHS cover.
    - Correspondence, 1994-1998 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Marketing Materials -- VHS Cover and Flyer, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Subseries VII.B. Press and Awards, 1993-1995; .44 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box
    This subseries contains publicity materials related to the film and awards received by the film and filmmakers. Materials include clippings, reviews, a publicity scrapbook, and photographs from the Emmy Awards.
    - Clippings, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Emmy Awards -- Photographs, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook, 1993-1995 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Subseries VII.C. Production Materials, 1992-2012; 7.38 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes and 6 record cartons; 10 Betacam_SP; 1 D-2; 2 U-matic; 5 VHS; 16.9 Gigabytes in 39 computer files
    This subseries contains materials related to the production of the film, such as photographs, video recordings, and a daily planner.
    - Daily Planner, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Electronic Recordings, 2003-2012; FA_MSS_558_ER_42
    - Photographs, 1993
      - Prints Level of Description (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Electronic Records, FA_MSS_558_ER_43
    - Slides by Simon Chaput, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Slides by Michael Paris, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Video Recordings
      - Complete Show, November 9, 1993 (Box 27, U-matic 558.0176)
      - Dennis Watlington and Omkari Williams -- Tapes 6-7, undated (Box 46, Vhs 558.0281)
      - Edited Master -- Finished Online -- Not Color Corrected, November 9, 1993 (Box 27, D-2 558.0174)
      - Hour 4 -- Dub, August 28, 1993 (Box 27, U-matic 558.0175)
      - Jack Ravage
        - Tape 1, June 7, 1993 (Box 28, Betacam sp 558.0601)
        - Tape 2, June 7, 1993 (Box 28, Betacam sp 558.0607)
        - Tape 3, June 7, 1993 (Box 28, Betacam sp 558.0600)
      - "The Making of the Untold West: Black Cowboys" -- Produced by Daedalus Productions
        - Electronic Recordings, 2003-2012; FA_MSS_558_ER_41
        - "The Making of the Untold West: Black Cowboys", August 1993 (Box 25, Vhs 558.0102)
        - "The Making of the Untold West: Black Cowboys", undated (Box 28, Vhs 558.0589)
        - Master Press Tape, August 9, 1993 (Box 28, Betacam sp 558.0582)
        - Reels 1-4, undated (Box 32, Vhs 558.0336)
        - Reels 5-6, undated (Box 32, Vhs 558.0451)
        - Tape 3, August 9, 1993 (Box 27, Betacam sp 558.0119)
        - Tape 4, August 9, 1993 (Box 28, Betacam sp 558.0604)
        - Tape 5, August 9, 1993 (Box 28, Betacam sp 558.0603)
        - Tape 6, August 9, 1993 (Box 27, Betacam sp 558.0125)
      - Master -- No Breaks, December 6, 1993 (Box 29, Betacam sp 558.0557)
      - Spot Clips, August 28, 1993 (Box 24, Betacam sp 558.0571)
  - Subseries VII.D. Research, undated; 1.23 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box and 1 cassette box; 1 Hi8
    This subseries includes research materials used in the making of the film, such as an article and a video recording.
    - Article, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Rough Ryders Stunts, undated (Box 35, Hi8 558.0751)
  - Subseries VII.E. Screenings and Festivals, 1994-1995; .69 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box and 1 medium flat box
    This subseries includes materials related to the screening of the film and participation in film festivals. Materials include a poster, program, and festival press.
    - Poster, circa 1994 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Program and Press, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Series VIII. Lock-Up: The Prisoners of Rikers Island and Beat Down: The Case of Raymond Alvarez, 1986-2000; 9 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box, 6 record cartons, 2 cassette boxes, and 1 card box; 8 Betacam_SP; 2 Betacam; 25 audiocassette; 2 Digital_Betacam; 1 D-2; 1 MiniDV; 8.05 Gigabytes in 11 computer files
  This series covers two related films in terms of subject matter, Lock-Up: The Prisoners of Rikers Island and Beat Down: The Case of Raymond Alvarez, both released circa 1994. Lock-Up is about life inside Rikers. It focuses on the the Nancy Figuerora hospital ward and the incarcerated individual James Mirabel, who was born in a prison and later died in one. Materials related to the film's production, marketing, and screening include a scrapbook, poster, photographs and negatives, and film elements (such as master copies, audio interviews, and certain scenes) on various media. Beat Down follows Raymond Alvarez, another incarcerated individual at Rikers Island who was the victim of correctional officers' brutality. Materials related to the production and screening of the film consist of correspondence with Alvarez, audio interviews, a master video recording, and film festival programs.
  Arranged into two subseries and alphanumerically within each one.
  - Subseries VIII.A. Lock-Up, 1986-2011; 6.65 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box, 5 record cartons, and 1 cassette box; 2 Digital_Betacam; 9 Betacam_SP; 1 audiocassette; 2 Betacam; 7.5 Gigabytes in 11 computer files
    This subseries consists of materials related to the film, Lock-Up. Materials include correspondence with James Mirabel, a publicity scrapbook, audio and video recordings, shoot photographs, case material on James Mirabel, an earlier film on prisons produced by Nina Rosenblum, and festival programs.
    - Awards, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence
      - Mirabel, James, 1991-1994 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Other Incarcerated Individuals, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Marketing Materials, 1994
      - DVD Cover, FA_MSS_558_ER_44
      - Postcard and Statement (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Press
      - Recidivism -- Tapes 1-2 -- Dub, July 14, 1994 (Box 25, Digital betacam 558.0116)
      - Recidivism -- Tapes 3-4 -- Dub, July 14, 1994 (Box 25, Digital betacam 558.0117)
      - Scrapbook, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Production Materials
      - Audio Recordings
        - Interviews, undated; FA_MSS_558_ER_109
        - Nancy/HBO, undated (Box 62, Audiocassette 558.0039)
      - Electronic Recordings and Photograph, 2004-2011; FA_MSS_558_ER_45
      - Photographs, Negatives, and Slides, circa 1994 (Box 10, Folder 9-12)
      - Video Recordings
        - #25 -- Master, August 14, 1991 (Box 24, Betacam sp 558.0574)
        - "Inside Stories from the War on Drugs" -- Produced and Directed by Nina Rosenblum, undated (Box 24, Betacam sp 558.0577)
        - Italian Master Recording, undated; FA_MSS_558_ER_117
        - Lock-Up: The Prisoners of Rikers Island, undated (Box 29, Betacam sp 558.0552)
        - Lock-Up: The Prisoners of Rikers Island, undated (Box 29, Betacam sp 558.0553)
        - Lock-Up: The Prisoners of Rikers Island, undated (Box 29, Betacam sp 558.0554)
        - Lock-Up: The Prisoners of Rikers Island, undated (Box 30, Betacam sp 558.0545)
        - Lock-Up: The Prisoners of Rikers Island -- Master, undated (Box 24, Betacam 558.0575)
        - Lock-Up: The Prisoners of Rikers Island -- Master, undated (Box 24, Betacam 558.0570)
        - Rikers Medal Ceremony -- Master, October 11, 1991 (Box 32, Betacam sp 558.0460)
        - Tape 2 -- Master, July 9, 1991 (Box 24, Betacam sp 558.0573)
    - Research Material
      - Electronic Records, circa 1990-1992; FA_MSS_558_ER_46
      - "Marion: The Toughest Prison in America" -- Produced and Directed by Nina Rosenblum for ABC's 20/20 -- Dub, undated (Box 24, Betacam sp 558.0578)
      - Mirabel, James -- Case Information, 1986-1992 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Screenings and Festivals, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Subseries VIII.B. Beat Down, 1991-2000; 3.88 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box, 1 record carton, 1 card box, and 1 cassette box; 24 audiocassette; 1 Betacam_SP; 1 D-2; 1 MiniDV
    This subseries consists of materials related to the film, Beat Down. Materials iclude correspondence with Raymond Alvarez, case information, audio and video recordings, and festival programs.